<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<concept id="Admins">
  <title>Admins and User-Roles</title>
  <conbody>
    <ul>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#overview">Overview</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#purpose">Purpose of this Feature</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#adminCreation">Creating an Admin</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#addSpocs">Add a SPOC</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#addTeamMember">Add a Team Member</xref></li>
    </ul>

    <section>
      <title id="overview">Overview</title>
      <lines>
        This page provides information on the all user-roles within the PDU OSS Deployment Tracking Tool.
      </lines>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title id="purpose">Purpose of this Feature</title>
      <lines>
        Here are the user-role types:
      </lines>
      <ol>
        <li>
          <b>User:</b> The default user-role. Only CRUD operations allowed on Booking, Deployment
          and Product-Type artifacts.<br/>
          <b>Sub User-roles (NOTE: Once the user is added to these areas, the permissions they provide applies to other main user-roles as well): </b>
          <ul>
            <li>
              <b>SPOC:</b> Is Deployment based permission user-role. The user only needs to have the 'User' user-role to appear in the SPOC multi select on a given Deployment.
              This allows the user to have the permissions to edit Bookings created for that Deployment and user will get emails about any Bookings for Deployments, that they are SPOC of.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Team Member:</b> Is Booking based permission for the user. The user only needs to have the 'User' user-role to be allowed to be a Team Member of a Team.
              This allows the user to have the permissions to edit Bookings assigned to the Team, that they are member of.
            </li>
          </ul>
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Admin:</b> In addition to 'User' privileges, Admins can perform CRUD operations
          on Hardware, Product-Flavour, Team, RA, Program artifacts, Users and Roles.<br/>
          Also Admins has the permissions to do the following:
          <ul>
            <li>
              Enable 'Cross RA Sharing' on Deployments.
            </li>
            <li>
              Edit 'Admins Only' Product Configuration in Deployments.
            </li>
            <li>
              Use 'Custom Team' assignment when creating a Booking.
            </li>
            <li>
              Edit Special Permissions of, and assign Roles to Non-Admin and Non-Super-Admin users.
            </li>
            <li>
              Create and Edit Non-Admin and Non-Super-Admin Roles.
            </li>
          </ul>
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Super-Admin:</b> In addition to 'Admin' privileges, Super-Admins can perform CRUD
          operations on Admins users. This role-type has no restrictions.
        </li>
      </ol>
      <lines>
        <b>NOTE:</b> When editing a started Booking, there are fields that cannot be edited regardless of the user-role.
      </lines>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title id="adminCreation">Creating an Admin</title>
        <ol>
          <li>
            When logged in as a Super-Admin, the user must click on their username in the
            navigation bar.
          </li>
          <li>From the revealed dropdown menu, click on 'Users'.</li>
          <li>In the 'Users' page, find the person the user wishes to make an Admin and click 'Edit' button.</li>
          <li>Below the 'Roles' heading click on the dropdown and select 'admin'.</li>
          <li>Click 'Save' button. This user is now an Admin.</li>
        </ol>
        <lines>
          <b>NOTE:</b> Only users who have logged into DTT at least once can be made Admins.
        </lines>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title id="assigningSpecialPermission">Assigning Special Permissions</title>
      <lines>
        Special Permissions for a resource are granted to a specific user on individual basis.
      </lines>
        <ol>
          <li>
            When logged in as an Admin or Super-Admin, the user must click on their username in the
            navigation bar.
          </li>
          <li>From the revealed dropdown menu, click on 'Users'.</li>
          <li>In the 'Roles' page, click 'Create new Role'.</li>
          <li>In the 'Name' field enter the name of the Role.</li>
          <li>Below the 'Permissions' heading click 'Add Permission'</li>
          <li>In the 'Path' field enter the path of the resource.</li>
          <li>Tick the boxes which specify the CRUD permission to be granted for the resource.</li>
          <li>Click 'Save' button. This Role will now be created.</li>
        </ol>
        <lines>
          <b>NOTE:</b> Only users who have logged into DTT at least once can be made assigned Special Permissions.
          <b>NOTE:</b> Certain features/functions require 'admin' or 'superAdmin' role. Simply granting CRUD permissions on a resource of not enough. Examples include: User/Role related operations, Cross RA Sharing for Deployment, Custom Team for Booking.
        </lines>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title id="roleCreation">Creating a Role</title>
        <ol>
          <li>
            When logged in as an Admin or Super-Admin, the user must click on their username in the
            navigation bar.
          </li>
          <li>From the revealed dropdown menu, click on 'Roles'.</li>
          <li>In the 'Roles' page, find the person the user wishes to assign special permissions to and click 'Edit' button.</li>
          <li>Below the 'Permissions' heading click 'Add Permission'</li>
          <li>In the 'Path' field enter the path of the resource.</li>
          <li>Tick the boxes which specify the CRUD permission to be granted for the resource.</li>
          <li>Click 'Save' button. This user will now have Special Permissions assigned.</li>
        </ol>
        <lines>
          <b>NOTE:</b> Certain features/functions require 'admin' or 'superAdmin' role. Simply granting a User a Role with CRUD permissions for a resource of not enough. Examples include: User/Role related operations, Cross RA Sharing for Deployment, Custom Team for Booking.
        </lines>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title id="addSpoc">Add a SPOC</title>
        <ol>
          <li>
            When logged in, the user must click on 'Deployments' in the
            navigation bar.
          </li>
          <li>From there update each Deployment to add the new SPOC.</li>
          <li>In the selected Deployment edit page, click the 'SPOC(s)' multi select.</li>
          <li>Enter the name into search field and then select the name from list provided.</li>
          <li>Click 'Save' Button. This user is now a SPOC of that Deployment.</li>
        </ol>
        <lines>
          <b>NOTE:</b> Only users who have logged into DTT at least once can be made a SPOC.
        </lines>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title id="addTeamMember">Add a Team Member</title>
        <ol>
          <li>
            When logged in as a Admin and the Admin of the Team being updated, the user must click on 'Organisation' in the
            navigation bar.
          </li>
          <li>From the revealed dropdown menu, click on 'Teams'.</li>
          <li>In the selected 'Team' Edit page, Add User by using User's signum (username).</li>
          <li>Enter signum into the field and click the plus button.</li>
          <li>Click 'Save' button. This user is now a Team Member of that Team.</li>
        </ol>
        <lines>
          <b>NOTE:</b> Only users who have logged into DTT at least once can be made a Team Member.
        </lines>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
