<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<concept id="customFilters">
  <title>Custom Filters</title>
  <conbody>
    <ul>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#overview">Overview</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#purpose">Purpose of this Feature</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#supportedFilters">Supported Artifacts for Filters</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#usingFilters">Using Filters</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#savingFilters">Saving Custom Filters</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#deletingFilters">Deleting Custom Filters</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#globalFilters">Global Filters</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#deploymentFilters">Deployment Filters</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#productFilters">Product Filters</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#bookingFilters">Booking Filters</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#bookingStatisticsFilters">Booking Statistics Filters</xref></li>
    </ul>

    <section id="overview">
      <title>Overview</title>
      <lines>
        This page provides information on custom filter functionality.
      </lines>
    </section>

    <section id="purpose">
      <title>Purpose of Custom Filters</title>
      <lines>
        Filters provide the ability to reduce the contents of tables and calendars down to a specified subset of data.
        As there are many Artifact fields the user may want to reduce lists by, the tool provides filters for core fields.
        Any combination of filters can be used together to reduce tables / calendars into even more specialised subsets of data.
        For quick access to regularly used custom filter configurations, the user can use the custom filter save feature.
      </lines>
    </section>

    <section id="supportedFilters">
      <title>Supported Artifacts for Filters</title>
      <lines>
        The list below specifies each DTT Artifact that currently supports filtering functionalities:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>Deployments</li>
        <li>Products</li>
        <li>Bookings</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="usingFilters">
      <title>Using Filters</title>
      <lines>
        To access and use filters, the user must:
      </lines>
      <ol>
        <li>
          Access the Artifacts list-view / calendar page and click the 'Show Filters' button.
        </li>
        <li>
          From the range of filter dropdown options, select one and choose a value from it to filter by.
        </li>
        <li>
          Results in the table / calendar will now be filtered by the chosen value for that field.
        </li>
        <li>
          Selecting another filter will reduce the table / calendar further.
        </li>
        <li>
          Entering a search-value in the text box (where available) will again filter the table / calendar further.
        </li>
      </ol>
      <lines>
        Additionally, some filters reduce the options available from other filter drop-downs.
        These filter-reductions act the same way for each Artifact filter and are detailed below for the relevant Statistics:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <b>Program:</b> RA filter options reduced to ones associated with the specified Program.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>RA:</b> Team and Deployment filter options reduced to ones associated with the specified RA. When RA value is selected, it's retained as the user's preference for the current session.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="savingFilters">
      <title>Saving Custom Filters</title>
      <lines>
        After selecting any number of filters, the user has two options for saving a custom filter:
      </lines>
      <ol>
        <li>
            <b>As a Bookmark:</b> This saves the custom filter as a URL bookmark for your browser.<br/>
            Bookmarks are convenient for sharing with other users as they can then access the same custom filter set-up as the User who created it.
        </li>
        <li>
            <b>To the Users Profile:</b> This saves the custom filter with a unique name to the Users profile.<br/>
            Saving a filter to the profile means that the same filter can be quickly selected again from the "custom filters" dropdown on the list-view page.
        </li>
      </ol>
    </section>

    <section id="deletingFilters">
      <title>Deleting Custom Filters</title>
      <lines>
        To delete a filter from the Users profile, the user must:
      </lines>
      <ol>
        <li>
          Select the desired filter from the "custom filters" dropdown on the list-view page.
        </li>
        <li>
          Select the "trash-can" icon that appears beside the "custom filters" dropdown.
        </li>
        <li>
          Accept the "delete custom filter?" alert panel that appears.
        </li>
      </ol>
    </section>

    <section id="globalFilters">
      <title>Global Filters</title>
      <lines>
        Listed below is information on filters that appear in every page and have the same effect.
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <b>Name Text-Box:</b> Only include Artifacts that have a name including the specified value.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Program:</b> Only include Artifacts that are associated with the specified Program.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>RA:</b> Only include Artifacts that are associated with the specified RA.
          Selected RA value is retained as the user's preference for the current session in the Deployments, Bookings Calendar, Products and Statistics pages.
          It can be changed by changing the RA value from one of the mentioned pages, or cleared by clearing the RA selection using 'x' button shown near the RA.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Team:</b> Only include Artifacts that are associated with the specified Team.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Product-Type:</b> Only include Artifacts that are associated with the specified Product-Type.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Created By:</b> Only include Artifacts that were created by the specified person.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="deploymentFilters">
      <title>Deployment Filters</title>
      <lines>
        Listed below is information on each Deployment filter and how they can be used:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <b>Status:</b> Only include Deployments that have the specified Status.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Label:</b> Only include Deployments that have the specified Label.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="productFilters">
      <title>Product Filters</title>
      <lines>
        Listed below is information on each Product filter and how they can be used:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <b>Product-Flavour:</b> Only include Products where the Parent Deployment has the specified Product-Flavour.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Infra-Type:</b> Only include Products where the Parent Deployment has the specified Infra-Type.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="bookingFilters">
      <title>Booking Filters</title>
      <lines>
        Booking Filters are shown by default in the bookings page. Listed below is information on each Booking filter and how they can be used:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <b>Program:</b> Only include Bookings that are associated with the specified Program.
          Note: Program value is required. If no value is selected; it will be auto-populated by the corresponding RA selected value.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>RA:</b> Only include Bookings that are associated with the specified RA. The calendar is not shown if no RA is selected.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Deployment:</b> Only include Bookings that are associated with the specified Deployment.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Label:</b> Only include Bookings that has Deployments that are associated the specified Label.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Start-Time After:</b> Only include Bookings where the start-time comes after the specified value.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>End-Time Before:</b> Only include Bookings where the end-time comes before the specified value.
        </li>
      </ul>
      <lines>
        Additional to the above features, Bookings have the following extra filter-related features:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>
          Booking filters can be set by selecting the 'Bookings' button of any RA, Team or
          Deployment from their respective list or view page.
        </li>
        <li>
          The tool also auto-populates the Deployment, Product and Team fields for new Bookings
          in the 'Create Booking' modal if values for their filters are selected.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="bookingStatisticsFilters">
      <title>Booking Statistics Filters</title>
      <lines>
        Booking Statistics are handled at 3 levels:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>Globally.</li>
        <li>Per Deployment.</li>
        <li>Per Deployment and Booking Team.</li>
      </ul>
      <lines>
        Certain Booking Statistic filter may be refer to values from Artifacts that are separate but associated with a Booking.
        This detail is provided below with any other relevant information on each Statistic filter.
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <b>Start-Time After:</b> Only include Bookings where the start-time comes after the specified value.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>End-Time Before:</b> Only include Bookings where the end-time comes before the specified value.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Program:</b> Only include Bookings where the Parent Deployment is associated with the specified Program.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>RA:</b> Only include Bookings where the Parent Deployment is associated with the specified RA.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Team:</b> Only include Bookings where the Parent Deployment is associated with the specified Team.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Deployment:</b> Only include Bookings that are associated with the specified Deployment.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Product-Type:</b> Only include Bookings that are associated with the specified Product-Type.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Shared Bookings:</b> Additionally, include Bookings that are children (Sharing) of other Bookings (Shareable).
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Empty Deployments:</b> Additionally, include Deployments that have no Bookings.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
