<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<concept id="globalSearch">
  <title>Global Search</title>
  <conbody>
    <ul>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#overview">Overview</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#purpose">Purpose of this Feature</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#usage">Usage</xref></li>
    </ul>

    <section>
      <title id="overview">Overview</title>
      <lines>
        This page provides information on the Global Search functionality of the PDU OSS Deployment Tracking Tool.
      </lines>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title id="purpose">Purpose of this Feature</title>
      <lines>
        The purpose of this feature is to allow a user to search for and find Artifacts by any key-value within the tool.
      </lines>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title id="usage">Usage</title>
      <p><b>Accessing the Global-Search Functionality:</b></p>
      <lines>
        When logged-in, the user must go to the home-page to access the global-search functionality.
        The home-page can be accessed by clicking the 'Ericsson DTT' icon in the nav-bar.
        There are 2 types of searches that can then be performed: Simple and Complex.
        The usage for both search-types are detailed below.
      </lines>

      <p><b>Simple Search:</b></p>
      <ol>
        <li>
          Enter a search-value in the search-bars input-field.
        </li>
        <li>
          Click the search-button to find Artifacts of any type which contain any key-value(s) that
          partially-match the provided search-value.
        </li>
        <li>
          Search-results are displayed in a table below the search-field.
        </li>
      </ol>

      <p><b>Complex Search:</b></p>
      <ol>
        <li>
          Enter a search-value in the search-bars input-field.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Artifact-Type Parameter:</b> Optional - Select an Artifact-Type from the
          dropdown to only return results that match the provided Artifact-Type,
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Match-Value Parameter:</b> Optional - Select a match-value parameter from the dropdown
          to only return results where the provided search-value either partially/full matches,
          is either the start/end of an Artifacts key-value. Alternatively, select the 'by
          labels' option to only return Deployments which contain all label names specified.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Case-Sensitive Parameter:</b> Optional - Toggle the case-sensitive checkbox to only
          return results where the search-value case-matches an Artifacts key-value.
        </li>
        <li>
          Click the search-button to find Artifacts which match the provided search-value and
          filtering-parameters.
        </li>
        <li>
          Search-results are displayed in a table below the search-field.
        </li>
      </ol>

      <p><b>Viewing the Results:</b></p>
      <lines>
        A table outputs all search-results from the search-operation performed.
        The table can be sorted by any column in ascending/descending order by clicking on the individual headers.
        The table contains link to view/edit each of the Artifacts found.
      </lines>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
