<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<concept id="statistics">
  <title>Statistics</title>
  <conbody>
    <ul>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#overview">Overview</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#purpose">Purpose of this Feature</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#supportedStatistics">Supported Artifacts for Statistics</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#usingStatistics">Using Statistics</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="concept" href="#bookingStatistics">Booking Statistics</xref></li>
    </ul>

    <section id="overview">
      <title>Overview</title>
      <lines>
        This page provides information on Statistics functionality.
      </lines>
    </section>

    <section id="purpose">
      <title>Purpose of Statistics</title>
      <lines>
        Statistics are analytical findings and are used to provide the user with useful information about Artifacts within DTT.
        These Statistics are calculated using various mathematical formulas with numerical data found across a selection of Artifacts.
        The analytical findings are then presented to the user through the forms of tables and various sorts of charts.
      </lines>
    </section>

    <section id="supportedStatistics">
      <title>Supported Artifacts for Statistics</title>
      <lines>
        The list below specifies each DTT Artifact that currently supports Statistical functionalities:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>Bookings</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="usingStatistics">
      <title>Using Statistics</title>
      <lines>
        To access and view Statistics, the user must:
      </lines>
      <ol>
        <li>
          Select 'Statistics' from the nav-bar.
        </li>
        <li>
          Select which Artifact they want to view Statistics for from the nav-bar dropdown.
        </li>
        <li>
          The user will be taken to the selected Artifacts Statistics page.
        </li>
      </ol>
    </section>

    <section id="bookingStatistics">
      <title>Booking Statistics</title>
      <lines>
        These Statistics are useful for providing information about Bookings that may not be visible otherwise.
        Statistical information on Bookings are grouped by associated Deployment and by what Team made the Booking.
        The Booking Statistics are broken into 3 levels - Globally, by associated Deployment, and by associated Deployment and Team the Booking was made for.
        For each level you can view the following Statistics:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <b>Total Bookings:</b> How many Bookings occurred.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Total Duration:</b> The total sum, in days, of every Bookings start-date to end-date duration.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Average Duration:</b> The average Booking duration, in days, calculated by dividing the Total Duration by Total Bookings.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Date Utilisation:</b> How many days were booked between the oldest Bookings start-date and the newest Bookings end-date.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Daily Activity:</b> The total sum of how many times a Booking occurred on each day of the week.
        </li>
      </ul>

      <lines>
        <b>Viewing the different Statistic levels</b>
        The different Statistic levels can be viewed in the following ways:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <b>Global:</b> From the top of the page, click the 'View Global Stats' button.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Deployment:</b> From the Statistics table, click the 'View Global Stats' button for any Deployment, OR;<br/>
          From the Global Statistics view, select any Deployment segment from a Graph
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Team:</b> From the Deployment Statistics view, select any Team segment from a Graph.<br/>
          <b>Note:</b> Team Booking Statistics are limited to those just for the prior selected Deployment.
        </li>
      </ul>

      <lines>
        <b>Booking Statistic Filters</b>
        Calculated Statistics can change depending on what Bookings are returned based off of selected filters.
        <b>NOTE:</b> Bookings statistics are only shown for past 2 months. Bookings which expired more than 2 months ago are automatically deleted by DTT, to keep performance of DTT to maximum.
        <xref href="../features/customFilters.xml#bookingStatisticsFilters">Follow this link</xref> to the 'Custom Filters' page for information on custom Statistics filters.
      </lines>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
