<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<task id="areas">
  <title>Requirement Areas (RAs)</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>
        A Requirement Area (RA) represents a whole unit or a subsection of a Product Development
        Group (PDG). Each Deployment artifact must have an associated RA.
      </p>
      <p><b>Objective</b></p>
      <p>Update an RA within the PDU OSS Deployment Tracking Tool.</p>
      <p>
        <b>NOTE:</b> No User is permitted to create an RA within DTT. Users with permissions are permitted to fill in only the available fields.
        The RA data is sourced from Team Inventory Tool. If anything is incorrect from the following: Name or Program, you must go to the Team Inventory Tool to fix it.
        Then DTT will be updated during next Team Inventory Tool check which happens once a day automatically.
      </p>
      <p>
        <b>Outline</b>
        <ol>
          <li><xref href="#openArea">Open the Requirement Areas List-View</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#updateArea">Update existing Requirement Area</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#enterDetails">Enter the Requirement Area Details</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#saveArea">Save Requirement Area</xref></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </context>
    <prereq>
      <p>To create a new Requirement Area the user must have the following:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>A pre-existing Program.</li>
      </ul>
    </prereq>
    <steps>
      <step id="openArea">
        <cmd>Open the RAs List-View</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the 'RAs' link in the navigation bar.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="updateArea">
        <cmd>Update existing Requirement Area</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the <b>Edit</b> button beside any RA in the list.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="enterDetails">
        <cmd>Enter the Requirement Area Details</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Enter the details as shown below.</p>
          <p><b>NOTE:</b> Any restrictions on the fields are outlined.</p>
          <ul>
            <li>
              <b>Name:</b>
              Name of the Requirement Area.
              Value is sourced from Team Inventory Tool and cannot be changed.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Program:</b>
              Must be an existing Program.
              Value is sourced from Team Inventory Tool and cannot be changed.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Booking Assignee User:</b>
              This field relates to the creation of JIRA Issue for Bookings.
              Select the User to be set as assignee to all JIRA Issues created for Bookings associated with this Requirement Area.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Maximum Booking Duration (Days):</b>
              Optional - The maximum number of days a Deployment can be booked for. Leave field empty for no limit.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Maximum Booking Advance (Weeks):</b>
              Optional - The furthest point in time a Deployment booking can finish, specified in weeks. Leave field empty for no limit.
            </li>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <b>User:</b>
                Select a User from a list.
                <b>NOTE</b> User must be signed in at least once to DTT for it to be visible in the list.
              </li>
              <li>
                <b>Permission Type:</b>
                Type of permission the User will have.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="saveArea">
        <cmd>Save Requirement Area</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Click the <b>Save</b> button, the RA will be updated, and the user will be
            redirected back to the view page for the modified RA.
          </p>
          <p>
            <b>NOTE:</b> RA will not save if any fields are invalid (invalid fields
            are highlighted in red).
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>An RA is updated in the PDU OSS Deployment Tracking Tool.</p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
