<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<task id="hardware">
  <title>Hardware</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>
        Hardware represents both independent blades and standalone rack servers.
      </p>
      <p><b>Objective</b></p>
      <p>
        Create a new Hardware within the PDU OSS Deployment Tracking Tool.
      </p>
      <p>
        <b>Outline</b>
        <ol>
          <li><xref href="#openHardware">Open the Hardware List-View</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#createHardware">Create New Hardware</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#enterDetails">Enter the Hardware Details</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#saveHardware">Save Hardware</xref></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </context>
    <prereq>
      <p>To create a new Hardware the user must have the following:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>A pre-existing Program.</li>
      </ul>
    </prereq>
    <steps>
      <step id="openHardware">
        <cmd>Open the Hardware List-View</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the Hardware link in the navigation bar.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="createHardware">
        <cmd>Create New Hardware</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the <b>Create new Hardware</b> button.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="enterDetails">
        <cmd>Enter the Hardware Details</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Enter the details as shown below.</p>
          <p><b>NOTE:</b> Any restrictions on the fields are outlined.</p>
          <ul>
            <li><b>Name:</b> Name of the Hardware.</li>
            <li><b>Hardware Deployment ID:</b> ID of Hardware Deployment.</li>
            <li><b>URL:</b> URL of the Hardware.</li>
            <li><b>Program:</b> Program of the Hardware.</li>
            <li>
              <lines>
                <b>Time Free Information:</b> This field defines how long the Hardware has been free.
                <b>NOTE:</b> This field is automatically set by the tool and cannot be manually adjusted.
                When the Hardware is created or dissociated from a Deployment, the field is given a timestamp representing the moment the Hardware became free.
                The timestamp is used to get an accurate measurement (days) on how long the Hardware has been free.
                When the Hardware is associated with a Deployment, the field becomes undefined which represents that the Hardware is now in use.
              </lines>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="saveHardware">
        <cmd>Save Hardware</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Click the <b>Save</b> button, the Hardware will be created, and the user will be
            redirected back to the view page for the newly created Hardware.
          </p>
          <p>
            <b>NOTE:</b> Hardware will not save if any fields are invalid (invalid fields
            are highlighted in red).
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>A New Hardware is created in the PDU OSS Deployment Tracking Tool.</p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
