<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<task id="teams">
  <title>Teams</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>
        A Team consists of Team-Admins and users. Teams in PDU OSS Deployment Tracking Tool (DTT) are
        used to associate Deployment with specific users.
      </p>
      <p>
        <b>NOTE:</b> No User is permitted to create a Team within DTT. Users with permission are permitted to fill in only the available fields.
        The Team data is sourced from Team Inventory Tool. If anything is incorrect from the following: Name, State, Requirement Area or Team Email, you must go to the Team Inventory Tool to fix it.
        Then DTT will be updated during next Team Inventory Tool check which happens once a day automatically.
      </p>
      <p><b>Objective</b></p>
      <p>Update an existing Team within the PDU OSS Deployment Tracking Tool.</p>
      <p>
        <b>Outline</b>
        <ol>
          <li><xref href="#openTeam">Open the Teams List-View</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#updateTeam">Update an existing Team</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#enterDetails">Enter the Team Details</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#saveTeam">Save the Team</xref></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </context>
    <prereq>
      <p>To update an existing Team the user must have the following:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>A pre-existing Requirement Area.</li>
        <li>Be granted edit permissions via Role or Special Permission, User must have logged into DTT at least once before.</li>
      </ul>
    </prereq>
    <steps>
      <step id="openTeam">
        <cmd>Open the Teams List-View</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the Teams link in the navigation bar.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="updateTeam">
        <cmd>Update an existing Team</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the <b>Edit</b> button beside any Team in the list.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="enterDetails">
        <cmd>Enter Team Details</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Enter the details as shown below:</p>
          <p><b>NOTE:</b> Any restrictions on the fields are outlined.</p>
          <ul>
            <li>
              <b>Name:</b> Name of the Team.<br/>
              <b>NOTE:</b> Value is sourced from Team Inventory Tool and cannot be changed.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>State:</b> Select the state for the Team, active or inactive.<br/>
              <b>NOTE:</b> Value is sourced from Team Inventory Tool and cannot be changed.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Team Email:</b> Enter a valid email address for the Team.<br/>
              <b>NOTE:</b> Value is sourced from Team Inventory Tool and cannot be changed.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Requirement Area:</b> Select an Requirement Area (RA). For associating an RA with the Team.<br/>
              <b>NOTE:</b> Value is sourced from Team Inventory Tool and cannot be changed.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Primary Team-Admin:</b> Select a primary Team-Admin.<br/>
              <b>NOTE:</b> User must have Admin permissions in DTT.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Secondary Team-Admin:</b> Optional - Select a secondary Team-Admin.<br/>
              <b>NOTE:</b> User must have Admin permissions in DTT. To remove Secondary Team-Admin, you can click '<b>x</b>' on the select field.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Users (Members):</b> Optional - Add users that are in the Team.<br/>
              <b>NOTE:</b> Only Users that have logged into DTT at least once, can be added as Users (Members) of the Team.<br/>
              Add User by using User's signum (username):
              <ol>
                <li> Enter signum into the field.</li>
                <li> Click the plus button.</li>
              </ol>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="saveTeam">
        <cmd>Save the Team</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Click the <b>Save</b> button, the Team will be updated, and the user will be
            redirected back to the view page for the modified Team.
          </p>
          <p>
            <b>NOTE:</b> Team will not save if any fields are invalid (invalid fields
            are highlighted in red).
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>A Team is updated in the PDU OSS Deployment Tracking Tool.</p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
